<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.9.2" xml:lang="en-US">
  <compounddef id="structngf__context" kind="struct" language="C++" prot="public">
    <compoundname>ngf_context</compoundname>
    <includes refid="nicegraf_8h" local="no">nicegraf.h</includes>
    <briefdescription>
    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>An opaque handle to a nicegraf rendering context.</para>
<para>A context represents the internal state of the library that is required for performing most of the library&apos;s functionality. This includes, but is not limited to: presenting rendered content in a window; creating and managing resources, such as images, buffers and command buffers; recording and submitting command buffers.</para>
<para>Most operations, with the exception of <computeroutput>ngf_init</computeroutput> and context management functions themelves, require a context to be &quot;current&quot; on the calling thread.</para>
<para>Invoking <computeroutput>ngf_set_context</computeroutput> will make a context current on the calling thread. Once a context is made current on a thread, it cannot be migrated to another thread.</para>
<para>The results of using resources created within one context, in another context are undefined, unless the two contexts are explicitly configured to share data. When contexts are configured as shared, resources created in one can be used in the other, and vice versa. Notably, command buffers created and recorded in one context, can be submitted in another, shared context.</para>
<para>A context mainatins exclusive ownership of its swapchain (if it has one), and even shared contexts cannot acquire, present or render to images from that swapchain.</para>
<para>See also: <ref refid="structngf__context__info" kindref="compound">ngf_context_info</ref> and <ref refid="group__ngf_1ga5689c89f5def935f949a03ec158fbf5b" kindref="member">ngf_create_context</ref>. </para>
    </detaileddescription>
    <location file="C:/Users/nicebyte/home/TERMINAL/nicegraf/include/nicegraf.h" line="1692" column="1"/>
    <listofallmembers>
    </listofallmembers>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
